DAYANARA **ALTAMIRANO**

Dayanara.altamirano@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/dayanara-altamirano

Dependable and motivated Programmer Analyst with 17 years of software development experience and 15 years in web development with full life-cycle involvement from requirements/design through implementation, support and maintenance. Experienced in relational database design and development in MS SQL Server and Oracle. Proficient in VB.net, ASP.NET, HTML and JavaScript. Excellent communications skills in both English and Spanish. A talent for troubleshooting and problem solving. Ability to quickly learn new applications, tools and programming languages and to adapt to any client systems. Self-motivated with a great attitude and able to work independently in a team environment and able to work with little supervision. Adapts easily to changes.

EXPERIENCE

AUGUST 2017 - PRESENT

HS COMPUTER SCIENCE INSTRUCTOR, CALVARY CHRISTIAN ACADEMY

https://www.ccaeagles.org/

- Create clear, engaging lessons to draw interest and develop students' ability to program in Python, Java, C# and Block base programming using MIT App Inventor.
- Earned Project Lead the Way certifications in Computer Science Essentials, AP Computer Science Principles and AP Computer Science A.
- Prepare curriculum, lesson plans and teach the following courses: Computer Science Essentials
 and Web Development with MySQL. also, Advanced Placement courses: Computer Science
 Principles and Computer Science A with 100% student pass rate.

MAY 2003 - AUGUST 2017

PROGRAMMER ANALYST, IQOR

https://www.igor.com/

- Worked closely with clients and program managers to establish specifications and system designs.
- Designed and implemented databases and data structures, stored procedures, views and triggers.
- Developed business applications using languages such as VB.NET, ASP.NET and C#.
- Worked on all stages of systems development life cycle, from requirement gathering to implementation.
- Integrated systems with various third-party APIs, including telephony/CTI middleware and web tracking.
- Worked on processes to manage client data via web services and ETL (SSIS) and VB.net console applications
- Designed and developed the following systems:
 - Automated Requisition & Training System
 - o Employee Management Information System
 - Customer Relationship Management System
 - Lead Management System

- Business Process Automation
- o Proprietary reporting and data management systems

DECEMBER 2002 – MARCH 2003

PROGRAMMER ANALYST, SIPECOM S.A

http://sipecom.com/

Designed and developed an MIS system in C#, ASP.Net, HTML, JavaScript and MS SQL 2000. I was responsible for database design for inventory and invoicing modules, and related client-facing modules.

MARCH 2001 – DECEMBER 2002

PROGRAMMER ANALYST, CYBER SYSTEMS - ECUADOR

- Responsible for design, development, and implementation of software solutions and related databases.
- Design, development and maintenance of a helpdesk web application with ASP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and back-end SQL Server 2000 database (structures, stored procedures, and triggers).
- Design and development of a Visual Basic system used by Clark Retail Enterprises to retrieve data from 1500 franchisees and transform/load to an Oracle database.
- Development of a mortgage pre-approval web application (www.mtgally.com), used by Bank of New York (1003 form).
- Design and development of a Visual Basic 6/Appforge rental information application for Palm Pilot, used to search and update legal, payment and repair information of tenant/property.

EDUCATION

OCTOBER 2002

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS, ESPOL

(POLYTECHNIC SCHOOL OF ECUADOR) http://www.espol.edu.ec/

MARCH 2019 (IN PROGRESS)

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS, BOSTON

UNIVERSITY

SKILLS

- VB.NET
- APS.NET
- JavaScript
- C#
- HTML
- Python
- Familiar with Agile methodology.

- CSS
- Oracle 8i/10g
- MS SQL Server
- MySQL
- Excellent communications skills
- Bilingual: English and Spanish